Register of the Hugh Gibson papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Hugh Gibson papers
1900-1983
56000
Hoover Institution Archives
131 manuscript boxes, 26 oversize boxes, 22 envelopes, 1 sound disc, memorabilia (92.4 linear feet)
Diaries, writings, correspondence, reports, minutes of meetings, photographs, and printed matter relating to American foreign relations, international disarmament, the League of Nations, and relief work in Europe during World Wars I and II. Diaries from 1918 also available on microfilm (1 reel). Food mission diaries of 1946 and 1947 are also available at http://www.hoover.org/library-archives/collections or at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org/
Gibson, Hugh, 1883-1954.
Access
Collection is open for research. Food mission diaries of 1946 and 1947 are also available at http://www.hoover.org/library-archives/collections or at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org/
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1956, with additional increments in 2013, 2014, and 2015.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Diaries from 1918 also available on microfilm (1 reel). Food mission diaries of 1946 and 1947 are also available at http://www.hoover.org/library-archives/collections or at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org/
Separated Materials
Some publications, newspapers, and pamphlets have been transferred to the Hoover Institution Library, see Appendix for list.
Biographical Note
1883 August 16 Born, Los Angeles, California
circa 1898 Attended Los Angeles Military Academy
circa 1900 Attended Pomona College
1907 Graduated, École libre des sciences politiques, Paris
1908 Took the Diplomatic Service Examination
1908-1909 Secretary, American Legation, Tegucigalpa, Honduras
1909-1910 Second Secretary, American Embassy, London
1910 Private secretary to the Assistant Secretary of State, Washington
1911 Clerk, Department of State, Washington
1911-1913 Secretary, American Legation, Havana, Cuba
1913 Observer, elections for Constituent Assembly of Santo Domingo
1914-1916 Secretary, American Legation, Brussels; liaison between Herbert Hoover and the Belgian government for the Commission for Relief in Belgium
1916 First Secretary, American Embassy, London
1917 Assigned to State Department - War Missions Author, A Journal from Our Legation in Belgium Aide to Lord Balfour, British Minister of Foreign Affairs, during visit to the U.S. Attached to Belgian War Mission during visit to the U.S.
1918 First Secretary, American Embassy, Paris; advisor to General Pershing
1918-1919 Member, Interallied Mission to Countries of former Austro-Hungarian Empire
1919-1924 Envoy Extraordinary and Minister Plenipotentiary to Poland (Warsaw)
1922 Married Ynes Reyntiens, Brussels
1924 Attended Temporary Mixed Commission for the Reduction of Armaments, League of Nations, Geneva; maintained as Ambassador-at-Large, League of Nations
1924-1927 Envoy Extraordinary and Minister Plenipotentiary to Switzerland (Bern)
1925 Vice-Chairman, American Delegation, Arms Traffic Conference, Geneva
1926-1930 Chairman, American Delegation, Preparatory Commission for the Disarmament Conference, Geneva
1927 Delegate, Conference on Private Manufacture of Arms, Geneva Chairman of American delegation and conference, Conference for the Further Limitation of Naval Armaments (also called Tripartite Naval Conference or the Three Power Conference), Geneva
1927-1933 Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Belgium and Envoy Extraordinary Minister Plenipotentiary to Luxemburg (Brussels)
1928 Doctor of Diplomacy and Political Science, Universite Catholique de Louvain
1929 Birth of son Michael Francis, Brussels
1930 Delegate, London Naval Conference
Doctor of Law, Universite Libre de Bruxelles
1931 Doctor of Law, Yale University Observer, Conference of Experts for a Moratorium on Intergovernmental Debts (also called the London Conference or the International Conference of Ministers), London
1932-1933 Acting Chairman, American Delegation, General Disarmament Conference, Geneva
1933-1937 Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Brazil (Rio de Janeiro)
1935 American Representative, Mediatory Group to end the Chaco War between Bolivia and Paraguay; delegate, Chaco Peace Conference, Buenos Aires
1937 Author, Rio
1937-1938 Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Belgium and Envoy Extraordinary and Minister Plenipotentiary to Luxemburg (Brussels)
1938 Retired from foreign service
1939 Author, Belgium: The Country and Its People Vice-President, Belgian American Educational Foundation; Chairman, A.R.A. Association
1940 Escaped from France during German occupation European representative for the National Committee on Food for Small Democracies
1940-1941 Director General for Europe of the Commission for Polish Relief and the Commission for Relief in Belgium
1942 Author, The Problems of Lasting Peace (with Herbert Hoover)
1944 Author, The Road to Foreign Policy
1945 Author, The Basis of Lasting Peace (with Herbert Hoover)
1946-1947 Member, Herbert Hoover Food Mission (Herbert Hoover, Chairman)
1947 Member, Investigatory Committee for postwar German economic policies
1950 Death of Ynes R. Gibson
1952 Director, Provisional Intergovernmental Commission on Movements of Migrants from Europe (ICEM)
1954 December 12 Died, Geneva, Switzerland
Scope and Contents note
The Hugh Gibson papers consist of diaries, writings, correspondence, reports, minutes of meetings, photographs, and printed matter relating to American foreign relations, international disarmament, the League of Nations, and relief work in Europe during World Wars I and II. Gibson's diaries of 1918 are also available on microfilm, and his food mission diaries of 1946 and 1947 are available at http://www.hoover.org/library-archives/collections or at http://digitalcollections.hoover.org/
The first increment was acquired in 2013 (boxes 153-155) and is comprised of family correspondence and an address book. The bulk of the correspondence is letters sent to Ynes Gibson and maintains the original arrangement of the creator.
The second increment (boxes 156-157) was acquired in 2014 and is comprised of correspondence, Ynes Gibson's diaries, photographs, and news clippings, speeches, and correspondence regarding Gibson's death.
League of Nations.; Disarmament.; International relief.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; World War, 1939-1945--Civilian relief.; Belgium--Foreign relations--United States.; Brazil--Foreign relations--United States.; Poland--Foreign relations--United States.; Switzerland--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--Belgium.; United States--Foreign relations--Brazil.; United States--Foreign relations--Poland.; United States--Foreign relations--Switzerland.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Diplomats--United States.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1911-1955 (Boxes 1-9)
  Scope and Contents note
  Bank statements, bills, clippings, identification cards and laissez-passers, insurance policies, legal papers, military record, and tax forms, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Accounts (Box 1)
    - Disallowed through loss of exchange, while Minister to Poland - Correspondence re relief bill, 1922-1930
    - For the Committee on Public Information, 1918
    - With Macy's
    - With the State Department, including salary statements and per diem allowances
      - 1911-1914
      - 1921-1927
      - 1932-1942
    - With various banks
      - Banque H. Lambert, 1934-1935
      - Banque Populaire Suisse, 1926
      - Banque St. Phalle, 1929
      - Credit Suisse, 1926-1927
      - Farmers' Loan and Trust Company, 1918
    - Guarantee Trust Company of New York, 1924-1933; 3.0 folders
    - National City Bank of New York (Box 2)
      - 1922-1933
      - 1933-1936
      - 1953
    - National Metropolitan Bank, 1924-1926
    - Security - First National Bank of Los Angeles, 1933-1936
    - Societe Generale de Belgique, 1923-1934
    - Union de Banques Suisses, 1926
  - Articles and press clippings on Hugh Gibson (hereafter Gibson)
  - Attorneys (Chapman and Chapman, Los Angeles)
    - 1930-1933
    - 1934-1937
  - Autograph requests (Box 3)
  - Automobiles
    - General
    - Bills (gas, repairs, etc.)
    - Insurance
      - General
      - Cadillac Limousine
      - Cadillac Toledo
      - Packard
    - Permits, driver's licenses, etc.
  - Bills
    - Paid, 1923-1933
    - Paid, 1923-1933 (Box 4)
    - Unpaid, 1924-1927
  - Biographical data
  - Bonds, stocks
  - Books, magazines
  - Cards (entry, identity, membership, visiting)
  - Clothing
  - Clubs
  - Death (Box 5)
    - Condolences
    - Notices and obituaries, 3.0 folders
    - Tributes - Bohemian After Glow Party, New York, 1955 October 30
  - Fishing, hunting
  - Friends - List of names and addresses
  - Guns
  - Health [See also: CORRESPONDENCE, Bourgeois, Maurice and Ferrero, Constantin]
  - Home furnishing
  - Homes (Box 6)
    - General
    - In Geneva
  - Honorary membership in the Patriotic Order Sons of America, 1951
  - Hotels
    - 1922-1929
    - 1930-1935
  - Insurance
  - Invitations
  - Laissez-passers
  - Laissez-passers, 2.0 folders (Box 7)
  - Letters of introduction sent to, or written by, Gibson
  - Letters of introduction and recommendation for Gibson himself, written by Herbert Hoover and Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1918-1919
  - Letter of appreciation for Gibson's cooperation written by Henry L. Stimson, 1933
  - Miscellaneous
  - Passports
  - Pets [See also: CORRESPONDENCE, Jacquet, Mr.; Lister, Winifred H. and Picton, Harry] (Box 8)
  - Poster collection
  - Retirement from foreign service, 1938
  - Servants
  - Speaking engagements
  - Taxes
  - Telegram account
  - Travel, 2.0 folders (Box 9)
  - U.S. Army - Officers' Reserve Corps
  - Wedding
    - General
    - Congratulations sent to Hugh and Ynes
  - Will
  - Wine cellar
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1902-1954 (Boxes 10-67)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Unidentified (Box 10)
    Unidentified correspondents probably include Walter Lippman, Maurice Pate, Maude Simonson, Lewis Strauss, "Jimmy" James Dunn, Gilchrist Stockton, Robert E. Tod, Charles de Kerchore, Peter Keena, and Anthony Lyell. Specific notes available in folder.
  - General
    - A-F
    - G-N (Box 11)
    - O-Z (Box 12)
  - A.R.A. Association, N.Y., 1925-1933 (Box 13)
  - Aaroe, B., 1952
  - Abele, Clarence A., Capt., 1919-1927
  - Abingdon, Lady, undated
  - Academie Diplomatique Internationale, Paris, 1932
  - Academy of Political Science, N.Y., 1930-1932
  - Achenbach, Frederick, 1926
  - Achilles, Theodore C., 1954
  - Ackerman, Carl, 1921
  - Ackerman, Ernest R., 1929
  - Adamovicz, Dominik, 1922
  - Adams, C. Stacy, 1931
  - Adams, E. D. [See also: Hoover War Library], 1920-1929
  - Adatci, M., 1928-1929
  - Addams, Jane, 1926
  - Addinson, Thomas, 1922
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1920
  - Adler, Cyrus, 1920
  - The Aeroplane, London, 1933
  - Affairs, Washington, D.C., 1930
  - Agence Belge Des Grandes Editions, Brussels, 1928-1929
  - Aghnides, A., 1931
  - Aguiera, Francisco Gutierrez, 1928
  - Ahlefeldt, P., 1931
  - Akeley, Mary L. Jobe (Mrs. Carl), 1928-1929
  - Akerson, George, 1927-1929
  - Alba, Duke of, 1927
  - Albin, Pierre, 1919
  - Aldrich, Mr., 1942
  - Algara de Terreros, Angel, 1952-1954
  - Allard, Josse, Baroness, undated
  - Allen, Frederick H., 1924-1929
  - Allen, Henry T., Maj. Gen., 1921
  - Allen, Jay, 1927-1932
  - Alles, Fred L., 1929
  - Almeida, Oscar, 1934
  - Ambrose, William H., 1924
  - American Ambassador, Brussels, undated
  - American Association for International Conciliation, N.Y., 1924
  - American Chamber of Commerce, London, 1930
  - American Club of Antwerp, 1930-1933
  - American Club of Brussels, 1931
  - American Committee to Aid the University of Nymegen (Holland), N.Y., 1949
  - American Council on NATO, N.Y., 1953
  - American Embassy, Brussels, 1924-1927
  - American Female Guardian Society, N.Y., 1930
  - American Foundation, N.Y., 1930
  - American Friends Service Committee, Philadelphia, 1929-1930
  - American Legation, Athens, undated
  - American Polish Chamber of Commerce and Industry in the U.S., N.Y., 1920
  - American Red Cross, Washington, D.C., 1924
  - American Relief Administration, N.Y., 1920-1924
  - Amory, Copley, Jr., 1922
  - Anckarsvard, Charles, 1930
  - Andersen, Ibart(?), Jr., 1920
  - Anderson, Chandler P., 1918
  - Anderson, Eleanor Garnett W., 1924
  - Anderson, Larz, 1931
  - Anderson, P. A., 1931
  - Andres, E., 1926
  - Andrews, Adolphus, 1927
  - Andrews, Arthur J., 1920
  - Andrews, Philip, Adm., 1923-1924
  - Andrews, William Whiting, 1918-1924
  - Annuaire du corps diplomatique et consulaire, Geneva, 1930
  - Ansembourg, Gaston d', 1930
  - Anstey, R. W., 1923
  - Arct, Stanislaw, 1923-1931
  - Argus Pressclipping Service, N.Y., 1925-1926
  - Armee du Salut, Brussels, 1932
  - Armour, Allison V., 1931
  - Armour, Norman [See also: DISARMAMENT CONFERENCES, Preparatory Commission, Second Part and General Disarmament Conference], 1924-1953
  - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1924-1928
  - Army and Navy Co-operative Society, Ltd., London, 1929-1930
  - The Arnett Athenaeum, Oklahoma City, 1932
  - Arnold, Marion, 1927
  - Arnott, Noel, 1927
  - Arrowsmith, H. W., 1928-1929
  - Ashley, James A., 1927 (Box 14)
  - Askenazy, Szymon, 1919-1921
  - Assche, Marquis d', 1919-1929
  - Association Suisse pour la Societe des Nations, (E. Bovet), Lausanne, 1924-1925
  - Astor, J. J., Maj., 1930
  - Atherton, Ray, 1927-1933
  - Atkinson, Henry A. (The Church Peace Union, N.Y.), 1921
  - Atwood, William G., 1924
  - Aubert, Theodore (Entente Internationale contre la IIIe Internationale, Geneva), 1932
  - Auchincloss, Charles C., 1952
  - Auchincloss, Gordon, 1919-1920
  - Auckarsvard, Charles d', 1924
  - Auckenthaler, Dr., 1925
  - Backus, E. Burdette, Rev., 1931
  - Baels, Mr., 1927
  - Baetens, Fernand, 1930
  - Bailey, James G., 1923
  - Bailey, Walter C., 1920
  - Baillet-Latour, Guy, Count, and Countess Elisalex (Liz) de, 1929-1933
  - Baker, Fred, 1922
  - Baker, George Barr, 1919-1929
  - Baker, Josephine (Mrs. James Blair), 1930
  - Baker, Newton D., 1925
  - Baker, Philip Noel, 1926-1932
  - Baker, Thomas S. [See Merle-Smith, Van S., September 18, 1920]
  - Baldwin, Elbert F., 1920-1927
  - Baldwin, Frederick W., 1925-1926
  - Baldwin, Mary A., undated
  - Baldwin, Philip S. [See also: DIPLOMATIC POSTS, Poland, Relief Work, Correspondence], 1920-1933
  - Ballairs, Roger M., Capt., 1930
  - Ballenbergh, Leigh, 1922
  - Bannerman, R. C., 1929
  - Barber, A. B., Col., 1921
  - Barker, Lew Ellis F., 1924-1932
  - Barlow, Walter Jarvus, 1922
  - Barnes, Howard R., 1923
  - Barnes, Julius H., 1924-1926
  - Barnes, Robert L., 1924
  - Barneville, M. F. de, 1927-1931
  - Barni, Margaret, 1929
  - Barnum, Mary G. (Mrs. O. Shepard), 1928-1929
  - Barrows, Albert L., 1920
  - Barrows, David Prescott, 1920-1924
  - Bartels, Cynthia J., 1931
  - Bartels, Earl G., 1921-1931
  - Barton, Alex, undated
  - Baruch, Bernard M., 1927
  - Bates, Marie Alice, 1925
  - Bathon, Wingrove, 1920
  - Baudoin, Prince, 1948-1951
  - Bavaria, Lori, Duchess, and Duc Buby of, 1953
  - Baxter, Norman W., undated
  - Bay, Charles A. [See: Yrureta-Goyena y Errazu, Don Joaquin]
  - Beal, Boyston A. [See also: SUBJECT FILE, Rogers Bill, Correspondence of Gibson], 1920-1942
  - Beaupre, Mary M., 1930-1933
  - Beck, James M., 1927
  - Beck, William Hopkins, 1923-1926
  - Beckton, Jean (Mrs. Hugh A.), 1929-1930
  - Beebe, William, 1953
  - Belden, Perry, 1920
  - Belin, F. Lammot, 1922-1933
  - Bell, Edward Price (Box 15)
    - 1915-1918
    - 1919-1924
    - 1926-1930
  - Bell, Elliot, 1952
  - Belmont, Perry, 1921
  - Benson, 1953
  - Bent, Ernest F., 1930-1932
  - Bent, Mattie, S. F. (Mrs. H. K. W.), 1932
  - Bentley, Thomas, 1920
  - Bentwick, V. Cavendish, 1922
  - Berenson, 1921
  - Berli, Antonina (Mrs. Adolph Berli), 1952
  - Besterman, Walter M., 1950-1953
  - Beughem, Irone de, 1928
  - Beukelaer, Louis Xavier de, 1931-1932
  - Biddle, Eleanor, 1926
  - Bishop, Roland P., 1922
  - Bishop, William Warner, 1924
  - Bisping, Helen de, 1923
  - Bissing, Moritz von, Baron, 1916
  - Blair, Percy, 1921-1923
  - Blair, Seymour, 1918
  - Blaisdell, Donald C., 1953
  - Blake, Gilson G., Jr., 1929-1932
  - Blaker, Dorothea C., 1918
  - Blanc y Menocal, Guillerme de, 1929
  - Blanck, G. de, 1927
  - Bland, George Nevile Maltby, 1930-1931
  - Blandy, C., Mrs., 1950-1954
  - Bliss, Tasker H., Gen., 1921
  - Bliss, Mrs., undated
  - Bliss, Robert Woods [See also: SUBJECT FILE, Rogers Bill, Correspondence of Gibson], 1918-1933
  - Bloodgood, William D., 1933
  - Blount, Daniel L., 1919-1933
  - Boal, Pierre de L.
    - 1919-1926
    - 1927-1954
  - Boifeuillet, John F., Col., 1933
  - Bomburg (?), Jacques, 1954
  - Bonney, M. Therese, 1926
  - Borchgrave, Ruth de, 1928
  - Borg, Carl Oscar, 1931-1946
  - Borowski, Adm., 1920-1921
  - Borum, Neal D., 1930-1931 (Box 16)
  - Borum, Wylie G., 1929-1930
  - Bory, Mr., 1927
  - Bosch, Elisa, 1932
  - Boswell, Walter O., Lt. Col., 1926
  - Botcine, Pierre, 1926
  - Botella, Cristobal [See also: SUBJECT FILE, Gibson, Ynes], 1927
  - Bouillon, H. Franklin, 1918
  - Bourgeois, Maurice, 1929
  - Bouton, Edward H., 1923
  - Bowles, F. T., Rear Adm., 1918
  - Bownton, Horace R., 1921-1952
  - Brabant, Duc of, 1928
  - Brackett, Frank P., 1928-1929
  - Brainard, David L., Gen. [See also: SUBJECT FILE, Chaco War, Correspondence, Diplomatic], 1925
  - Bree, Firmin van, 1922-1954
  - Bree, Parish of (Belgium), 1919
  - Breitstein, P. H., 1927
  - Brener, Carl, 1929
  - Bridge, Helen L., 1925-1927
  - Briey, Renaud de, Count, 1932
  - Briggs, Lawrence P., 1934
  - Briggs, Mitchell Pirie, 1932
  - Briggs, William H., 1926
  - British Embassy, Paris, 1926
  - Bronson, Mrs., 1929
  - Brooke, Mark, 1925
  - Brooks, Walter, 1915-1925
  - Broom, John H., 1951
  - Brown, Arnold, 1932
  - Brown, Edward D., 1952-1953
  - Brown, Harrison, 1930-1931
  - Brown, Isabel Grant, 1929
  - Brown, Milton M., 1927-1931
  - Brown, Philip Marshall, 1920-1932
  - Brown, Walter Lyman [See also: DIPLOMATIC POSTS, Poland, Relief Work, Correspondence], 1920
  - Browne, Philip, 1931
  - Buchanan, Edward W., 1921-1932
  - Buckler, William H., 1929-1930
  - Bucklin, George A., 1918
  - Buell, Raymond Leslie, 1929
  - Buero, 1926
  - Buisseret, Francois de, 1930
  - Bullard, Arthur, 1924-1932
  - Bullock, Hugh, 1953
  - Bundy, Harvey H., 1931
  - Burdett, William C., 1928-1932
  - Burdette, Clara B. (Mrs. Robert J.), 1926
  - Burdette, Franklin L., 1932
  - Burge, R. T., 1922
  - Burger, Morris, undated
  - Burland, E., 1919-1922
  - Burnham, Hubert, 1931
  - Burnham, Roderick and Gayle, 1954
  - Burroughs, Josephine Isadore, 1931
  - Burton, Theodore E., 1925-1928
  - Bushea, Frances F. (Mrs. W. J.), 1926
  - Butler, Mrs., 1925
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1925
  - Butterworth, William, 1928
  - Byington, Homer Morrison, 1931-1932
  - Byrne, William H., 1928
  - Cable, Bertha Lovejoy, 1932
  - Cable, Philander L., 1929
  - Cabot, John Moors, 1933-1936
  - Caffery, Jefferson, 1926-1933
  - California Grape Grower, San Francisco, 1925
  - Call, Mabel S. (Mrs. Arthur D.), 1924
  - Cameron, C. R., 1933
  - Camp, Loretta F., 1953
  - Campbell, P. Llambi, 1933-1934
  - Cantacuzene Speransky, Julia, Princess, 1927-1928
  - Carbonell, Jose Manuel, 1936
  - Carey, William F., 1936
  - Carmichael, James J., 1930
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, N.Y., 1925
  - The Carnegie Institute, Pittsburgh, 1929
  - Carpenter, Clayton, undated
  - Carpenter, Ford Ashamo, 1925-1929
  - Carr, Harry C., 1930-1932
  - Carr, Lenore Czarnecki, 1934
  - Carr, Wilbur J., 1920-1936
  - Carriel, Mary Turner, 1927
  - Carroll, Joseph W. [See also: SUBJECT FILE, Rogers Bill, Correspondence of Gibson], 1924-1933
  - Carter, E. C., 1925-1926
  - Cartier, E. de, Baron, 1920-1932
  - Carton de Wiart, Adrien, Maj. Gen., 1930
  - Carton de Wiart, Juliette, 1934
  - Carton de Wiart, Baron de, 1930-1934
  - Cartwright, Henry A., Capt., 1932
  - Carvalho, Carlos Delgado de, 1936
  - Case, J. F., Maj., 1927
  - Casenave, 1919
  - Cash, Oliver H., 1926
  - Castle, A.(?), Brig., 1922 (Box 17)
  - Castle, William R., Jr. [See also: SUBJECT FILE, Rogers Bill, Correspondence of Gibson, and DISARMAMENT CONFERENCES, Preparatory Commission, Second Part]
    - Undated
    - 1918
    - 1920
    - 1921
    - 1922
    - 1923
    - 1924
    - 1925
    - 1926
    - 1927
    - 1928
    - 1929 (Box 18)
    - 1930
    - 1931
    - 1932
    - 1933
    - 1934-1938
    - 1954
  - Castro Maya, Raymond O. de, 1936
  - Causey, W. B., Col., 1921-1928
  - Cavalcanti de Lacerda, Felix de Barros, 1935
  - Cazzelett, V., 1941-1943
  - Cecil, Eleanor, 1925
  - Cecil, Robert, Lord, 1930-1932
  - Chadbourn, Philip H., Capt., 1921-1926
  - Chamberlain, Lee, 1936
  - Chance, Leslie G., 1953
  - Chandler, Charles Lyon, 1935-1936
  - Chapman, Frazer and Lindley, 1953
  - Chapman, Ward, 1922
  - Cheney, Charles H., 1928
  - Chermont, E. L., 1933
  - Chester, S. Beach, 1929
  - Chevrel, Yvonne, 1952
  - Chevrillon, Louis, 1919-1930
  - Chilean Delegation to the League of Nations, 1926
  - Chilton, Billy, 1928-1934
  - Churchill, John, 1942
  - Chute, Mervyn, Mrs., 1954
  - Ciechanowska, Gladys (Mrs. John), 1952-1954
  - Ciechanowski, John, 1920-1954
  - Ciechanowski, Stanislav, 1952-1954
  - Clark, J. Reuben, 1919-1936 (Box 19)
  - Clark, Kenneth, 1930
  - Clark, Sarah R., 1921
  - Clarke, Ernest P., 1930
  - Clarke, Louise Harvey, 1921-1932
  - Clary, Resy, Princess, 1936
  - Clary, Sophie, Countess, 1928-1954
  - Clary, Alfred, Prince, 1921-1954
  - Clary, Carlos, Prince, and Princess Felicie, 1920-1922
  - Clary, Lidi, Princess, 1935-1954
  - Clary, Siegfried, Count, 1925
  - Clary Kinsky, Princess, 1927-1933
  - Clinchy, Dr., 1950
  - Clynans, H., 1930
  - Coakley, Henry L., 1925
  - Coates, Charles B., 1953
  - Cobb, Candler, 1923
  - Cobian, Eduardo, 1927-1934
  - Cochrane, L. J., 1920-1925
  - Coen, A. [See: BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, Accounts with various banks, Societe Generale de Belgique]
  - Cognard, Count, 1927
  - Cohn, Edith A. (Mrs. Morris), 1923
  - Colcord, Samuel, 1926-1932
  - Cole, 1930
  - Coleman, W. H. A., 1924-1933
  - Collier, John, 1927
  - Collyer, Bert E., 1926
  - Connes, Frank, 1924
  - Connor, W. W., 1929
  - Cook, Arthur E., 1923
  - Cook, O. W. E., 1929
  - Cook, T. C., Maj., undated
  - Coolidge, Archibald Cary, 1921-1928
  - Coolidge, Calvin, 1924
  - Cooper, Harriet M. (Mrs. James), 1953
  - Cooper, John C., 1921
  - Cooper, Ken [See: Hooper, Jessie J.]
  - Cooper, Merian C., 1921-1933
  - Copeland, A. Reilly, 1932
  - Copland, Douglas, 1954
  - Corcoran, George Eustis, 1928
  - Corey, Ida G., 1929
  - Corse, Frederick M., 1922
  - Coshman(?), Eleanor, undated
  - Coster, Henrietta Fox (Mrs. Norman), 1922-1936
  - Coster, Norman B., 1920
  - Coulson, Basil I. B., 1930
  - Council on Foreign Relations, N.Y., 1921-1932
  - Cowan, Denys, 1924-1928
  - Cox, Capt., 1941
  - Cox, Raymond E., 1928-1936
  - Coxe, Francis Travis, 1919
  - Crane, Richard, 1919-1926
  - Craig, Nancy, undated
  - Craig, Robert Howell, 1929-1954